Zach Cohen

https://www.zach-cohen.com 480.444.8097 / zachtylercohen@gmail.com

My education and practical work experience has been focused on how we interact with the world around us. Through design, I am mindful of the entire lifecycle of a product and its business impact. My goal is to help create products and shape experiences that have a positive impact on people's lives.

Skills

- Design for enterprise software and web/mobile experiences
- Conduct both qualitative and quantitative research to correctly frame problems
- Create detail oriented workflow maps and wireframes
- Emphasize the relationship aspect of cross-functional teams
- Experience developing products in an Agile framework

InVisionSketchFigmaFramer XMicrosoft OfficeAxure RPHTML/CSS capabilitiesAdobe Creative SuiteZeplin

Experience

Mar. 2019 - Present

Integrate / Phoenix, AZ / Product Designer

- Established a Design System guild to guide best practices and overall progression.
- Partnered with product management to conduct discovery and define software features.
- Led design and product-informed strategy for several product development teams.
- Prototyped, user tested, and worked with engineering to implement and ship designs.

Sept. 2018 - January 2019

InEight / Scottsdale, AZ / UX Interaction Designer (Contract)

- Translated design vision established through research to update legacy product.
- Worked closely with product and development teams to add and refine product features.
- Led user experience optimization alongside key stakeholders and product management.
- June 2018 August 2018

Nucleus Marketing Lab / Phoenix, AZ / User Researcher (Contract)

- Helped recognize user behavior and re-frame product development goals through qualitative and quantitative research and analysis.
- Used accumulated data to help provide brand strategy insight for both regional and national companies.

January 2017 - May 2017

a verynice design studio / Los Angeles, CA / UX Strategy Intern

• Worked closely with the lead strategist to develop MVPs and design artifacts for startups and non-profit organizations.

Education

Graduated May 2018

Designlab / Remote

User Experience Design certificate

Studied and applied UX principles to a diverse group of industry specific applications including healthcare, social media, and e-commerce. Individually led several projects through each phase of the UX process.

Graduated May 2017

Woodbury University / Burbank, CA

B.A. Interdisciplinary Studies, Psychology and Interior Architecture Emphases

AIAS (American Institute of Architectural Students), IIDA (International Interior Design Association), Zone V Photography Club. Thesis on the intersection between architecture, psychology, and philosophy.

Initiatives

May 2017

Give All (giveall.io): Give All connects non-profit employees and bootstrapped entrepreneurs with the creative and strategic design methods they need. Contains downloadable PDFs and accompanying video walkthroughs to help you learn how to build a brand, create a digital presence, and better position your organization.

Interests

Cooking and trying new foods, gaming, landscape and architectural photography, reading, writing